# **ALEX KIM**

ALXK.IO | PROVIDENCE, RI | AKIMO6@RISD.EDU | +1 917 891 5667

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

An aspiring creative technologist with an interest in creative coding and generative design. I would like to design, build, and code tools for everyone. My goal is to constantly build upon a knowledge base and skill set through research and practice with programming-based frameworks.

A former chef of over 13 years, I have spent time training and working at numerous restaurants in New York City, San Francisco, and Kyoto, Japan. As a chef I have been mentioned through various media publications including Bon Appétit, Eater, and Hypebeast US & Japan.

## **EDUCATION**

RHODE ISLAND SCHOOL OF DESIGN, PROVIDENCE, RI SEPTEMBER 2006 - MAY 2008, SEPTEMBER 2022 - MAY 2023 Currently pursuing a BFA in Graphic Design.

POMONA COLLEGE, CLAREMONT, CA SEPTEMBER 2005 - MAY 2006

### **CERTIFICATES & PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

## **GOOGLE UX DESIGN PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE**

AUGUST 2022 - CURRENT (EXPECTED COMPLETION: SUMMER 2023)

UX foundations and experience with wireframes, prototypes, and user research.

## UNDERGRADUATE CODING CERTIFICATE, HARVARD EXTENSION SCHOOL

JANUARY 2021 - CURRENT (EXPECTED COMPLETION: SUMMER 2023)

A three course certificate for the foundational understanding of computer science and the art of programming through the use of algorithms, data structures, encapsulation, resource management, and software engineering through Java, R, Python, C, C++, PHP, JavaScript, Swift, and SQL.

## MAD ACADEMY, BUSINESS & LEADERSHIP PROGRAM, COPENHAGEN, DENMARK

**OCTOBER 2020** 

Intensive program for rising leaders in the Hospitality and Food Industry focusing on the need for functioning leadership in hospitality. Hosted by MAD Academy from chef René Redzepi of restaurant Noma and chef Magnus Nilsson of Fäviken. Attendee by invite to the inaugural session.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### UNTITLED.HAUS - FOUNDER & SOLE PROPRIETOR

DECEMBER 2020 - CURRENT

Online store for design, gastronomy, and art related media.

# SNOW PEAK, INC., PORTLAND, OR - EXECUTIVE CHEF

FEBRUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Opening chef for Japanese brand Snow Peak's flagship restaurant 'takibi' at their U.S. Headquarters.

## KIKUNOI HONTEN, KYOTO, JAPAN - STAGIER

SEPTEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

Three Michelin Kaiseki Cuisine in Gion-Maruyama. Chef Yoshihiro Murata.

### KAPPO SAKAMOTO, KYOTO, JAPAN - COOK

APRIL 2017 - JULY 2019

One Michelin Kappo Cuisine in the Gion District. Chef Ryuta Sakamoto.

## RINTARO, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - SOUS CHEF

AUGUST 2015 - MARCH 2017

California-Japanese Cuisine. Chef Sylvan Mishima Brackett.

#### BENU, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - COMMIS

JULY 2014 - AUGUST 2015

Three Michelin Modern Asian. Chef Corey Lee.

### KAJITSU, NEW YORK, NY - LINE COOK

AUGUST 2012 - FEBRUARY 2014

Two Michelin Shojin Ryori, Kaiseki Cuisine. Chef Ryuta Ueshima.

## LANTERN, CHAPEL HILL, NORTH CAROLINA - LINE COOK

JULY 2011 - JULY 2012

#### YAMAZUSHI, DURHAM, NORTH CAROLINA - COOK

MAY 2010 - JUNE 2011

## **INTERNSHIPS**

### NARU SOBA, HAMAMATSU, SHIZUOKA PREFECTURE, JAPAN - STAGIER

AUGUST 2017

## SOBA RA, HONJO, SAITAMA PREFECTURE, JAPAN - STAGIER

FEBRUARY 2016

Internship at a rural soba restaurant by invitation of author Nancy Singleton Hachisu.

### MAINE SEAWEED, STEUBEN, ME - INTERN

APRIL 2014 - JULY 2014

Harvesting and processing of various Atlantic Seaweeds.

# ROMERO FARMS, DIXON, NM - INTERN

MARCH 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2009

Internship at an organic farm in Northern New Mexico.

## **AWARDS & HONORS**

### WASHOKU WORLD CHALLENGE, 8TH COMPETITION

DECEMBER 2020

Finalist for an International Japanese Cuisine Competition by the Japanese Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry, and Fisheries.